在上一集中
Previously on "Transformers Prime..."
终极之锁的组装已进入最终阶段
Assembly of the Omega Lock is entering the final stage.
威震天正准备把地球数字化
Megatron is preparing to cyber-form Earth.
汽车人 锁定坐标
Autobots, lock on to those coordinates.
频谱分析确认
Spectrum analysis confirms
合成能量已经稳定
that the Synthetic Energon is stable.
可惜你无法眼看着自己的研究成果开枝散叶
But pity you won't live long enough to witness the fruits of your labor.
是你那高高在上的首领 想要除掉你们巨狰狞
Your high and mighty leader wanted your Predacons exterminated!
而我唯一的错误就是没有斩草除根
And my only mistake was not seeing the extermination through.
你应该在我面前保持野兽形态
You should have faced me as a beast!
动用所有剩余力量！
Globalize what remains of our forces.
在此与他决一死战！
This will be our last stand.
终极之锁的控制台在底层甲板
The Omega Lock's control station is located on the lower deck.
快！
Come on!
我正往那儿赶
I am making my way there now.
收到 救护车
Copy, Ratchet.
我们在目标处汇合
We will rendezvous at the objective.
阿尔茜 带领突击小队夺取终极之锁
R.C., lead stealth team to secure the Omega Lock.
通天晓 你带雷霆救援队突袭舰桥
Ultra Magnus, you and the Wreckers storm the bridge.
不能让霸天虎锁定设备目标
Prevent the Decepticons from targeting the device
一旦突击小队被拖住
if stealth team is delayed.
擎天柱 万一没能在终极之锁启动前把它抢下来
Optimus, if we fail to secure the lock before it's ready to deploy
要不要把它摧毁？
do we destroy it?
我不打算再次浪费复苏塞博特恩的机会
I do not intend to squander a second chance to restore Cybertron.
雷霆救援队！
Wreckers.
小蜂 烟幕 跟我来
Bee, Smokescreen... with me.
烟幕！
Smokescreen!
啊！
Raaaah!
你们先去
Go on without me.
你要开小差吗？
That isn't the mission.
我得先去做件事
There's something I need to do.
关掉它 震荡波
Shut it down, Shockwave.
我决不允许你危害地球！
I cannot allow you to harm Earth.
这个星球不会受到伤害
The planet will not be harmed...
毁灭的只不过是本地的物种
only its indigenous life-forms.
除非你跨过我的尸体！
Over my sparkless husk.
啊！
Aaah!
救护车 我们正接近你的位置
Ratchet, we're approaching your position.
什么？
What?!
该死！
Scrap.
进攻！
Attack!
轻装上阵 轻装上阵
Pack light. Pack light.
重质不重量
Pack smart.
幸好你还在这儿
I was hoping you'd still be here.
夺取舰桥！
Secure the bridge!
通天晓呼叫所有单位 我们要迟到了
Ultra Magnus to all units. We will be delayed.
声波又玩儿了一次传送的花招
Soundwave pulled one of his relocation tricks.
拉夫 能把我弄到战舰的舰桥上吗？
Raf, can you get me onto the warship's bridge?
当然能 我已经掌握了它的坐标
Sure, now that I have a fix on it.
但你怎么可能敌得过声波？！
But you won't have a chance against Soundwave.
有后援就行
I will if I have backup.
呃啊!
Eh... ah!
威震天陛下 终极之锁充能完毕 准备就绪
Lord Megatron, the Omega Lock is fueled and ready.
震荡波 启动终极之锁发射程序
Shockwave, commence Omega Lock firing sequence.
什么？噢 该死！
Eh! Oh, scrap!
没想到吧！
Surprise!
喝！
Hah!
别以大欺小啊！
Pick on someone your own size.
拉夫 好戏该开始了！
Raf, showtime!
真的要这样吗 杰克？
Are you sure about this, Jack?
上次能量流重叠…
Last time you crossed the streams...
动手 拉夫 快！
Do it, Raf... now!
好好享受暗影空间吧 老兄
Enjoy the shadow zone, dude.
快 得弄明白怎么驾驶这个大家伙
Come on. We need to figure out how to navigate this thing.
震荡波 准备发射…
Shockwave, prepare to fire the...
什么？
What?!
喔哇！
Whoa!
伙计 你是哪个驾校的？！
Dude, where'd you learn to drive?
快递到了！
Special delivery.
那边 对吧？
That way, right?
擎天柱 接着！
Optimus! Catch!
烟幕！
Smokescreen!
擎天柱 你必须用星辰剑毁掉终极之锁！
Optimus, you must use the Saber to destroy the Omega Lock.
这是拯救地球的唯一办法！
It is the onty way to save Earth!
星辰剑！
The Star Saber!
不！
No!
跟你的侦察兵一起回归火种源吧！
Prepare to join your scout in the Allspark.
威震天！
Megatron!
你夺走了我的声音！
You took my voice.
可你休想再夺走任何人的任何东西！
You will never rob anyone of anything ever again.
威震天陛下 不！
Lord Megatron! No!
我要替你报仇 主人！
I will avenge you, master!
红蜘蛛 别傻了！
Starscream! Do not be a fool!
现在你还扯什么该死的逻辑！
Curse you and your logic!
大黄蜂
Bumblebee!
你的声音…
Your voice...
我的声音 你说什么…
My voice? What are you...
我的声音！
my voice!
救护车 我的发声器回来了！
Ratchet, I have my pipes back!
没错 没错！我们听出来了
Yes. Yes, we noticed.
是塞博特恩网状物
The cyber matter...
这是唯一合理的解释
It is the only possible explanation.
看来曾经的战地医生终于兑现承诺了
It would seem the old field medic made good after all.
擎天柱呼叫所有单位 威震天已不复存在
Optimus Prime to all units.
太棒了！
Yes!
- 呜哇！\N- 雷霆救援队 夺取舰桥的任务完成得非常出色
Hooah!
并非我们所为 长官
It wasn't us, sir.
都是人类的功劳
The credit belongs to the humans.
哦耶！
Hoo-Yeah!
终极之锁掌握在我们手中
The Omega Lock is under our control.
我建议物尽其用
I propose that we put it to good use.
我同意 老朋友
Agreed, old friend.
通天晓 设定航向 飞往塞博特恩
Ultra Magnus, set course for Cybertron.
嘿 拉夫 跟你的笔记本小别几秒钟
Hey, Raf, if you could tear yourself away from your laptop for two seconds...
把自己传送过来 咱们一起去塞博特恩吧
grid yourself up here so we can get to Cybertron already.
等等 那是谁？
Wait. Who's that?
小蜂？
Bee?
呃啊 你的胳膊肘快捅进我的腰里了！
Eh... ah. Your elbow articulator is digging into my lateral flexor!
你打算一路都这样抱怨下去么？
Do you intend to whine for the duration of the voyage?
擎天柱 我…一直都没参透
Optimus, I... was never able to learn
震荡波对于网状物的研究
Shockwave's side of the cyber matter equation.
我们可能只有这些了
This may be all we ever have.
而塞博特恩要比地球大得多
And Cybertron is a much larger planet than Earth.
那么我们必须将网状物注入塞博特恩的核心
Then we must launch the cyber matter at Cybertron's very core.
注入原始天尊的心脏？
Into the heart of Primus himself?
指挥官 我们已经抵达火种源之井
Commander, we've arrived at the Well of all Sparks.
啊 多美的光辉啊！
Ahh. Such luster.
怎么了 我本来就是墙头草嘛！
What? I'm joining the winning team.
呀啊！
Aaah!
是那只巨狰狞
The Predacon.
尽管家园重获了维持生命的能力
Though our home world is once again capable of supporting life...
但我们仍有很多重建工作要做
we have much rebuilding to do.
也罢 我们会怀念远方这个家园的
Alas, we will miss our home away from home
还有这里的亲人
and the family we've made here.
逍遥法外的虎子 不会再打地球的主意吗？
If 'Cons are still out there, won't Earth be on their radar?
拉夫 只要你们需要我 需要我们做任何事情
Raf, if you ever need me, need us for any reason
我们就在太空桥的另一头
we're just a space bridge away.
而且 我们会得到妥善照顾\N你 杰克和神子 将继续为E部门效力
Besides, we'll be in good hands with
就算是半官方身份
In our semi-Official capacity.
哇喔 我们是探员了？
Whoa! We are Agents?!
是顾问
Consultants.
直到年龄符合要求
Until you're of age.
我相信E部门不会食古不化
I trust that Unit-E doesn't have any rules
拒绝招募一个老掉牙的汽车人顾问吧？
forbidding the enlistment of rusty, old Autobot consultants?
救护车 你竟然…
Ratchet? You of all...
没错没错！
Yep, yep, yep.
我知道自己的价值所在
I know where I am needed.
拉夫…
Raf...
我明白 小蜂
I know, Bee.
什么都不用说
You don't need to say anything.
以前我也没说过
I never did.
神子 我觉得现在…
Miko, I guess this is...
这段旅途我永生难忘
It's been quite a ride.
保持联络 杰克
Keep in touch, Jack.
别逼我回来追你
Don't make me hunt you down.
来日再会 老朋友
Until we meet again, old friend.